It's classic encounters of the funniest kind!
The Bugs Bunny/Road Runner Movie is a animation,
comedy, family film directed by Chuck Jones.
A collection of Warner Brothers short cartoon features, "starring"
the likes of Daffy Duck, Porky Pig and Wile.E.Coyote.
These animations are interspersed by Bugs Bunny reminiscing on past events and providing
links between the individual animations which are otherwise unconnected.
This 1979 feature-length compilation includes several of his best cartoons.
Among the 11 shorts shown in their entirety are the classics "Robin Hood
Daffy," "What's Opera, Doc?," "Bully for Bugs," and "Duck Amuck".
The Bugs Bunny Road Runner Movie provides a showcase not only for Jones's razor-sharp timing, but for the work of his exceptional crew, which
included designer Maurice Noble, writer Mike Maltese, composers Carl Stalling and Milt Franklyn, and voice actor Mel Blanc.
Bugs Bunny / Daffy Duck / Porky Pig / Marvin the Martian / Wile E. Coyote / Pepe
le Pew / Dr. I.Q. High / Hassan (voice), played by Mel Blanc.
Elmer Fudd (voice), played by Arthur Q. Bryan.
Road Runner (voice), played by Paul Julian.
Giovanni Jones (voice), played by Nicolai Shutorev.
Cavewoman (uncredited), played by Joan Gerber.
The Bugs Bunny/Road Runner Movie (originally entitled as The Great American Chase) is a 1979 American animated comedy package film directed by Chuck Jones, consisting of a
compilation of classic Looney Tunes/Merrie Melodies shorts (specifically those that Jones himself directed) and newly animated bridging sequences hosted by Bugs Bunny.
The bridging sequences, which had been produced in 1978, show Bugs at his home, which is cantilevered over a
carrot-juice waterfall (modeled on Frank Lloyd Wright's "Fallingwater" house in Bear Run, Pennsylvania).
The film was released to celebrate the 40th anniversary of Bugs Bunny.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.